Petri Yamamoto

Full Stack Developer

Dedicated and efficient full stack developer with 6+ years experience in application layers, presentation layers, and databases. Certified in both F/E and B/E technologies.

Spearheaded successful transition from LAMP stack to MEAN which cut latency by 40% and increased effectiveness of database administrators by 20%. Seeking to further improve HTML5 and CSS3 skills as the future full stack developer at Atmospheric Solutions.

- petri430yamamoto@gmail.com
- **J** 1 973 797 9183
- Singapore, Arizona
- nttps://github.com/petriyamamoto

Work Experience

HCL Singapore Pte Ltd

Junior Full Stack Developer

May 2015 - June 2018 | Remote

- Maximized applications' efficiency, data quality, scope, operability, and flexibility.
- Used various ideas from distributed computing, large-scale design, real-time data processing, data storage, ML, and AI to solve challenging dataset problems.
- Designed and implemented web applications along with 3rd-party software integrations as a web team liaison for all inter-departmental and customer-facing projects.
- Managed, optimized, and updated PHP databases as necessary.
- Developed app integration with REST/SOAP and other APIs for Google Maps, social media logins, payment processors, and other services.

Citiustech

Full Stack Developer

July 2018 - March 2021 | Princeton, New Jersey, United States

- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Liaised with back end developers, front end developers, quality assurance testers, and CTO as needed.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications and software with complete accuracy.

Skills

- Google Compute Engine
- Android and iOS App Development
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP
- Bootstrap & Angular JS
- jQuery, React, React Native, Node JS
- SQL Databases
- Ruby on Rails , Laravel , Django , Electron JS

Certifications

- Full-Stack Web Development with React Certification
- Front End Web Development Certificate
- Back End Web Development Certificate
- AWS Certified DevOps Engineer Professional
- Free Code Camp Full Stack Development Certification

Awards

Dev of the Quarter (Q3/2015) at Crazy Lazy Apps

Memberships

- Association for Women in Computing (AWC)
- Association of Information Technology Professionals (AITP)

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology, Computer Science

National University of Singapore

2010 - 2014 | Lower Kent Ridge Rd, Singapore 119077

Awards

- Bachelor of Information Technology
- Bachelor of Finance and Electronic Engineering